不正視聴!?
(天道)ここより世界に痛みを。
And now…
This world shall know pain.
神羅天征。
Almighty Push…
(サクラ)ゴホッ ゴホッ ゴホッ。
何なのよ これ。
Wh-What is this?!
どうして こんな…。
How could this hap—
ナルト 早く来てよ。
Naruto… Hurry!
お願い ナルト！
Please, Naruto!
(ナルト)どこだってばよ ここ。
Where are we anyway?
(ガマブン太)
敵は どこにおるんなら。
Where is the enemy?
(フカサク)どういうことじゃ
母ちゃん。
What's going on, Ma?!
Why didn't you Summon us
to the Leaf Village?
なして 木ノ葉の里に
口寄せせなんだんじゃ？
(シマ)ここが木ノ葉隠れの里じゃ。
This is the Hidden Leaf Village.
(ガマ吉)どういうことじゃ
シマばぁ。
What do you mean,
Granny Shima?!
あたりを よう見てみんさい。
Look carefully around you.
まさか！
It can't be…!
誰がこれをやったかは明白じゃ。
And it's obvious who did this.
自来也小僧の肩にいたときと
同じものを感じる。
I sense the same energies as when
we rode atop Jiraiya-boy’s shoulders.
綱手様 ご無事で。
(綱手)あぁ…。
あっ！
な なんだ これは!?
クッ！ 許さん… 許さんぞペイン！
《あっ！ 額のマークがない！
すでに 創造再生の術を解放されて
カツユ様に 全チャクラを！
このペインの術から
里の人々を守るために…。
これではもう…》
(イルカ)クッ！
大丈夫か？ イルカ！
(カツユ)すみません…。
皆様を包むだけで精一杯でした。
カツユ様のせいではありません…。
《イルカ : みんな
無事だといいんだが…》
Explosion! Sage Mode
Lady Tsunade, are you all right?!
Yes…
Wh-What is this?
You will not get away with this…
《いの : シズネさん…》
You will not get away with this, Pain!
The mark on her forehead is gone!
She has already released
her Mitotic Regeneration Jutsu
(チョウジ)ゲホッ ゲホッ！
and given all her chakra
to Lady Katsuyu.
In order to protect the villagers
from this Pain’s jutsu…
(チョウジ)父ちゃん！
(カツユ)チョウザさんなら大丈夫です！
あぁ よかった…。
She can no longer…
Are you all right, Iruka?!
Forgive me.
カカシ先生…。
It took everything…
just to cover you all.
((チョウジ : うぅっ…。
You are not to blame, Lady Katsuyu.
I just hope everyone else is all right.
Lady Shizune…
Pa!
Choza is all right.
Thank goodness.
Kakashi Sensei…
父ちゃん…。
僕をかばって…。
Pa…
You tried to protect me…
(カカシ)泣くのはあとだ チョウジ…。
Save the crying for later…Choji.
まだ動けるなら ペインの能力を
綱手様へ報告してくれ。
If you are able to move…
report to Lady Tsunade
about Pain's abilities.
A counter strategy is imperative!
(カカシ)すぐに対策を立てるんだ！))
カカシ先生からの最後の任務
俺 ちゃんと… 俺…。
Kakashi Sensei,
your last mission orders…
I-I com…
I completed the mission, Sensei!
任務完了しました 先生！
(キバ)うう… くっそ！
Damn!
(ツメ)しっかりしな キバ！
Hang in there, Kiba!
(キバ)ぐっ…。
いてて！
Ow!
うお～！
ヘッ… どうってことねえぜ。
(赤丸)ワン！
This is nothing.
(コウ)大丈夫ですか？ ヒナタ様。
Are you all right, Lady Hinata?
(ヒナタ)うん。 それより コウのケガを…。
Yes, but Ko, you’re injured.
ヒアシ様 ハナビ様の留守中に
ヒナタ様に何かあれば➡
If anything should happen to you during
Lord Hiashi and Lady Hanabi’s absence,
私の一生の恥になります。
I will be dishonored for life.
私のことなど 気になさらぬよう。
You need not concern yourself
with me.
ですから 余計です。
But I must!
If everyone is injured while
the head of the family is away,
宗家が出払っている今
みんながケガをしたままでは➡
私が叱られる。
I will be the one scolded.
ヒナタ様…。
Lady Hinata…
《それにしても➡
Still…this attack is…
この攻撃…》
(シカマル)ぐっ…。
(シホ)大丈夫ですか？ シカマルさん！
Are you all right, Shikamaru?!
ああ っつか…。
Yeah… But what's going on?!
何なんだよ こりゃ？
(シカク)無事か？ シカマル。
You okay, Shikamaru?!
どうにかな。
だが 足が折れちまってる。
I made it out, but my leg’s broken.
この攻撃に足１本なら
ラッキーだったと言うべきだな。
You should consider yourself lucky
if the only thing you suffered in
this attack was a leg injury.
ぶっちゃけ シカマルさん
私を かばってくれたんです。
Actually, Shikamaru…
shielded me.
それで ケガを…。
And that's how he got hurt.
Come on,
this is no time for tears.
おいおい
今は泣いてる場合じゃねえぜ。
こんな とんでもねえ術を
持っていながら➡
They possess this kind of jutsu,
but didn't use it from the start.
初めから こいつを
使ってこなかったっつうことは➡
ヤツらには 目的があったからだ。
Which means, they had a purpose.
And they fulfilled that purpose,
だが その目的を果たしたことで➡
so they changed from guerilla tactics
to an all-out offensive.
ヤツら 戦闘スタイルを
陽動のゲリラ戦から➡
戦略的な拠点破壊攻撃に
変えてきやがった。
ヤツらって？
Who's "they"?
木ノ葉に
これだけのことができる連中…。
Someone who can do this
much damage to the Leaf Village…
The only one I can think of
is the Akatsuki.
今は 暁しか考えらんねえ。
だな。
ヤツらの目的は もちろん…。
I agree…and their target
is none other than…
ああ。 うずまきナルト。
Yeah…
Naruto Uzumaki!
ナルト君!?
N-Naruto?!
Yes…
運に頼ってたんじゃ
命がいくらあっても足りねえが➡
I'll never have enough lives
if I rely on luck alone.
Still, I'm one lucky guy.
たしかに ラッキーだったぜ。
If you care enough to shed tears,
泣くくれぇなら ２発目が
来ねえことでも祈っててくれよ。
then pray we don’t get hit
with another one.
Naruto…
《ナルト…》
That's…
あれは…。
It’s Naruto!
ナルトだ！
《ナルト!?》
Naruto?!
探す手間が省けたな。
You saved us the trouble
of looking for you.
(小南)どうして こんな無茶を？
Why are you being so reckless?
これが 俺の正義だからだ。
This is…my justice.
《すべてのチャクラを
天道だけに集中した時の➡
The effectiveness of the jutsu
when all the chakra is concentrated
in Tendo is great,
術の効果は大きいけど
その分のリスクが高すぎる。
but it also increases the risks.
それに以前 この術を使った時より
５人の復活が遅い》
Not only that, the other five
are recovering much slower
compared to the last time
this jutsu was used.
私は これから あなたを看る。
紙分身は ここまでにするわ。
From here on out,
I'll be looking after you.
No more Paper Clones.
口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu!
どうやら６人 揃ったな。
Looks like all six have assembled.
(フカサク)綱手…。
Tsunade?
I am the Fifth Hokage!
私は 五代目火影だ！
(暗部)五代目様！
Lady Hokage!
先代たちの宝を 夢を蹂躙した
お前らは 絶対に許さん！
You trampled on the jewel,
the dreams of my predecessors.
I will not forgive you!
ここで火影として決着をつける！
I will settle this now as the Hokage!
少しは痛みを理解したようだな。
だが お前などに用はない。
It appears you now understand
a little about pain.
However…my business is not with you.
あるのは…。
My business is…
With me!
俺だろ！
こんなヤツらに 木ノ葉の火影が
出るまでもねえよ。
There’s no need for
the Leaf’s Hokage
to bother herself with
the likes of them.
ばあちゃんは ゆっくり
茶でも飲んでてくれ。
ナルト！
You just sit back and
sip some tea, Granny.
Naruto!
どうなったの!?
ここからじゃ。
What happened?!
I can’t tell from here.
すごいよ ペインの１人を
たった一撃で…！
It was amazing! He took down
one of the Pains in one swoop.
《ナルト… あんた！》
Naruto…you…
じじ様 ２人の懐かしい
背中が見えんかったか。
Gramps… Doesn’t he remind you
of those two?
そうじゃのう。
You’re right…
《ナルトちゃんは
先代を超えたようじゃ》
It seems Naruto-boy has
surpassed his predecessors.
うずまきナルト。
Naruto Uzumaki.
ケリ つけてやる！
Let’s settle this!
《天道の力 当分は
元に戻らない ならば…》
Tendo’s power won’t return
for quite some time.
In which case…
ガマ吉！
Gamakichi!
綱手のばあちゃんを
安全なところへ連れていけ！
Take Granny Tsunade to
someplace safe!
おっす！
ばあちゃん こっからは俺がやる！
Gotcha!
Granny, I’ll take over from here!
里のみんなには
手を出さねえように伝えてくれ。
Tell everyone in the village
to stay out of the way!
みんなをかばいながら戦うのは
逆に やりづれぇからな。
It’ll be difficult to fight while trying
to cover for them.
わかった。
なら カツユを連れていけ。
Understood.
But take Katsuyu.
I know she'll be useful to you.
少しは役に立つはずだ。
ヤツらの情報を持っている。
She has intel on them.
カツユちゃんよ ナルトちゃんの懐に
隠れておきんさい。
Katsuyu-girl… Keep yourself hidden
in Naruto-boy's clothes.
はい。
Yes, sir.
今 こんなこと聞くべきじゃ
ねえのかもしんねえけど➡
Now may not be the right time
to ask a question like this…
俺 自然エネルギーを身につけたから
わかんだってばよ。
But now that I've mastered
Nature Energy…
みんなのチャクラを
感じ取ることができる。
I'm able to sense everyone's chakra.
カカシ先生は
任務で里の外に出てんのか？
Is Kakashi Sensei on a mission
away from the village?
そうか。
I see…
行け ガマ吉！
Go, Gamakichi!
(畜生道)口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu.
師匠…。
Master!
綱手様！
Lady Tsunade!
サクラ もう大丈夫だ。
Sakura…
Everything is okay now.
はい。
Yes…
《お疲れさまでした 綱手様》
Thank you, Lady Tsunade.
口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu!
（２人）仙法 蛙鳴き！
– Sage Art! Frog Song!
影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
仙法 大玉螺旋丸！
– Sage Art! Giant Rasengan!
ブンちゃん ケンちゃん ヒロちゃん！
Bunta-boy! Ken-boy! Hiro-boy!
おっしゃ～！
Right on!
ナルト君
目の前のペインに忍術は効きません。
Naruto! Ninjutsu won't work
on the Pain standing before you.
忍術による攻撃は
すべて吸収されてしまいます。
He will absorb all your ninjutsu attacks.
なら 蛙組手だ！
Then we'll go with Frog Kumite!
ペインの目は繋がっています。
All the Pains are visually linked!
死角からの攻撃は➡
A blind-spot attack is meaningless
全員の視線を外さないと
無意味です！
unless you move out of the line
of view of every one of them.
なら 見えねえ攻撃 見せてやるぜ。
Well then… I'll show them
an attack they can't see.
この犬っころが！
You little mutt!
おんどりゃ～！
Take that!
せい！ 落ちろ！
Down with you!
He's falling.
(ガマケン)自分 不器用ですから。
You see, I’m ungraceful.
うりゃ！
おとなしゅうしとれ 犬っころ！
Stay still, you mutt!
《かわしたはずが これか》
I thought we dodged it…
《蛙組手は 己の周りにある
自然エネルギーを利用する。
Frog Kumite utilizes
the Nature Energy around you.
そのエネルギーが
ナルトの体の一部となって➡
The energy became part of
Naruto's body when he attacked Pain!
ペインを攻撃したんじゃ。
仙人モードは 危険感知も攻撃範囲も
並のそれじゃあらへんぞ》
In Sage Mode, both threat perception
and attack range
are enhanced way
beyond the ordinary.
チンタラしてる ヒマはねえ。
No time to waste here!
新術で一気に 終わらせてやる！
I’ll finish this with my new jutsu!
影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
そうか お前は仙人を。
I see… So you have become a Sage…
自来也先生と同じ術を
身に付けたようだな。
mastering the same jutsu
as Jiraiya Sensei.
自来也先生だと!?
Jiraiya…“Sensei”?
俺も自来也から 術を学んだ。
I also learned jutsu from Jiraiya.
自来也は 俺のかつての師だ。
He was once my master…
お前にとって 俺は兄弟子。
Which would make us sibling disciples.
同じ師を仰いだ者同士
理解しあえるはずだが。
Sharing the same master,
you and I should be able to
understand one another.
師は平和を望んでいた。
Our master desired peace.
ふざけるな！
Shut the hell up!
なんちゅうチャクラじゃ
父ちゃんが教えたんか？
Such massive chakra…
Did you teach him that, Pa?
いや。 わしも初めて見る。
No… I'm seeing it for
the first time too.
修業中 一度もあんなものを。
He never showed that
during our training.
何をするつもりじゃ
ナルトちゃんは？
What is Naruto-boy planning to do?
あの術は。
どうしたんですか？
What is that jutsu?
What is it?
ナルトのチャクラが…
そう まるで手裏剣のように。
Naruto's chakra is forming into…
Yes, almost like a shuriken.
風遁 螺旋手裏剣。 ナルト！
Wind Style: Rasen Shuriken?!
Naruto!
お前らのやった これの。
All that you've done here…
これのどこに 平和があるんだ！
Where's the "peace" in that?!
木を見て 森を見ていない。
You're only looking at the tree,
not the whole forest.
You don't know
the true meaning of peace.
お前には 平和の意味が
理解できていないだけだ。
おとなしく捕まれ。
So let yourself be captured.
お前の死が 平和へ繋がる。
Your death will lead to peace.
ふざけんなって
言ってんだろうが！
I told you…
to shut the hell up!
投げおった！
何じゃ？
He threw it!
What is that?!
Pa! The boy’s no longer in
Sage Mode.
しかしよ お前が
風遁を使えるようになるとはな。
It’s risky, but we must merge
with him now!
なんだよ 急に。
ちょっと思い出してよ。
We can’t! You see, the Nine-Tails
prevents us from merging!
確かに あのときは
誰も思わなかったよね。
Then what are we going to do?!
Naruto-boy came up with a way
only he can pull off!
風遁かぁ。
And that’s what
we’re about to do!
なんかさ
ちょっと響きがクールだよね。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
“Danger! Sage Mode Limit Reached”
おし！ 俺ってば
絶対 そいつをマスターしちゃお！
分身もできねえヤツが
偉そうに。
I’m counting on you, Geezer Sage!
うっせえよ！ クソー！
ヘヘヘ でもね 実は僕
ちょっとだけ使えるんだ 見てて。
Man…
Who’d have thought you'd
master Wind Style?
What makes you say that?
I was just thinking…
いくよ 風遁 大吸引！
Yeah, who would have
guessed back then?
お！
Huh?
The Wind Style?
ね？
で～!!
It has a nice ring to it, y'know.
それの どこが
風遁なんだってばよ！
そんなんだったら 俺だって！
いくぞ 風遁 おなら！
やめろ～！
なんで～!?
アホー アホー アホかー！
＜ナツたちの前に現れた
新生オラシオンセイス。
なすすべもなく
無限時計を奪われ➡
その 奪還作戦も失敗に終わり➡
生体リンクの封印も すべて解かれ➡
無限時計は その真の姿を現した。
そして 時が混乱を始める＞